<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>Mads Kristensen</author>
  <title>New AJAX features</title>
  <description>BlogEngine.NET just got new cool AJAX features using ASP.NET's client-callbacks feature.</description>
  <content>
		&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have requested that we added AJAX to certain parts of BlogEngine.NET, so we did. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Because of the rule of not using third party components, it is implemented using the build-in client-callback feature with some custom JavaScript. All in all very few lines of code was needed.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The calendar widget to the right on this site is now ajaxified for a more smooth navigation between months. The postback reloaded the page every time you navigated to a new month and that was not very cool. The performance is actually pretty descent I think.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The comments have also been AJAX enabled, so that when you write a comment, there is no postback anymore. It makes sure that the browser supports AJAX before enabling it, so that it falls back to normal postback behaviour on old browsers. The invisible CAPTCHA still works when the browser doesn’t support AJAX. I have never seen ajaxified comments on other blogs, so it might be an exclusive feature of BlogEngine.NET.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I cannot share the bits with you because &lt;a href="http://www.codeplex.com/blogengine/SourceControl/ListDownloadableCommits.aspx"&gt;CodePlex&lt;/a&gt; is having problems, so there is no access to the source code. CodePlex say they will be back online within 96 hours. In the mean time you can try out the new calendar widget and the AJAX comments by posting one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2007-04-13 00:00:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2007-04-16 23:48:36</lastModified>
  <tags>
    <tag>ajax</tag>
    <tag>blogengine</tag>
    <tag>javascript</tag>
  </tags>
  <comments>
    <comment id="20abc317-21e2-4a68-acbb-bae17b7d8639">
      <date>2007-04-14 03:53:36</date>
      <author>Joe</author>
      <email>jkaiser@dodgeit.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip />
      <content>Awesome! This engine is really starting to look good.  Keep it up.</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="7150b76c-8ab4-4134-a1b5-2985aba5a591">
      <date>2007-04-14 08:27:01</date>
      <author>Ted Jardine</author>
      <email>mail@ovalsquare.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip />
      <content>Keeping close tabs on this project. Great stuff! (where do you find the time?)

As to Ajax comments, you can find a real nice implemenation at http://cpalm.dk/blog/2006/08/03/ajax-and-umbraco.aspx ...now I'm going to post this comment and see how it compares ;-)</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="ca9a59ba-6bdb-4e70-a13d-750f2b85e67e">
      <date>2007-04-14 08:30:06</date>
      <author>Ted Jardine</author>
      <email>mail@ovalsquare.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip />
      <content>I'm sure you'll notice above that if there's a dash in the url, the link is broken. I guess once Codeplex is back up I could post a bug report there. And have noticed previously also the repeated comment items (&amp;quot;As to Ajax comments, you can find a real nice implementation at Keeping close tabs...&amp;quot;)</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="9e8c7079-1ba0-456f-8fd8-d038734581e2">
      <date>2007-04-14 12:36:03</date>
      <author>Mads Kristensen</author>
      <email>post@madskristensen.dk</email>
      <country>DK</country>
      <ip>127.0.0.1</ip>
      <website>http://www.madskristensen.dk/</website>
      <content>test</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="60d76ff6-f136-4079-8c22-0be324ef3fbe">
      <date>2007-04-16 22:59:27</date>
      <author>Mads</author>
      <email>post@madskristensen.dk</email>
      <country>dk</country>
      <ip>127.0.0.1</ip>
      <website>http://www.madskristensen.dk/</website>
      <content>mads</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="54cacdc3-697b-4474-8aee-eed8fd29d580">
      <date>2007-04-16 23:00:15</date>
      <author>mads</author>
      <email>mads@mads.dk</email>
      <country>dk</country>
      <ip>127.0.0.1</ip>
      <content>tasf</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="6a18af19-365e-40ea-a404-265d6049c734">
      <date>2007-04-16 23:05:39</date>
      <author>mads</author>
      <email>mads@mads.dk</email>
      <country>dk</country>
      <ip>127.0.0.1</ip>
      <content>asdf</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="da007ca7-8c36-4bec-8612-0f32edd44e5e">
      <date>2007-04-16 23:09:13</date>
      <author>mads</author>
      <email>er@strong.dk</email>
      <country>dk</country>
      <ip>127.0.0.1</ip>
      <content>asdf</content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories />
</post>