<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<page>
  <title>About Mads Kristensen</title>
  <description>Short bio of Danish developer Mads Kvist Kristensen</description>
  <content>
		&lt;p&gt;My full name is Mads Kvist Kristensen and I was born in Denmark in 1980. I received a business degree from college in 1999 and worked for a couple of years with economics and marketing at &lt;a href="http://www.rockwool.com"&gt;Rockwool A/S&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time I opened a wine importing company that sold various wines to super markets. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;It was while trying to create the website for the wine company that I got interested in web development and decided to put all my energy into it. So, I started the company &lt;a href="http://www.easywebdesign.dk"&gt;Easy Web Design&lt;/a&gt; and made about 50 websites in 3 years. &lt;a href="http://www.easywebdesign.dk/referencer/"&gt;Here’s a list of some of them&lt;/a&gt;. In the meantime I studied at &lt;a href="http://www.kts.dk/lygten/index.asp?afd=312&amp;amp;sid=798"&gt;Copenhagen Technical Academy&lt;/a&gt; on the Multimedia Design line. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;At that time I started my third company, WEBintelligence, specializing in search engine tracking. It was an online service that enabled homepage owners to track the activity of Google, Yahoo, Altavista and other search engines on their website and gave suggestions on how to improve their ranking based on the statistics collected. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;WEBintelligence was very fun, but when I got a fulltime job at Reaxion as a content management system developer, I ran out off time to continue the work. So, that was the end of WEBintelligence, but the urge for working with statistics was far from gone. &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;After 2 years at Reaxion, I got a position as Senior Developer at &lt;a href="http://www.traceworks.com/"&gt;Traceworks&lt;/a&gt; where I once again had the opportunity to work with statistics. The range of my responsibilities spans from system architecture to ASP.NET, Windows Form and Windows Services including framework design and class library development. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;In January 2007 I was then upgraded to Lead Developer in charge of front-end and business logic development. This position also includes responsibility for the overall code quality delivered by all developers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Coding principles&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I’m a strong believer of KISS – Keep It Simple, Stupid - so much in fact that I would go to great length to find the cleanest and simplest solution to any given problem. The reason for this is, that the simple solution is easier to maintain, extend and reuse and the better you become, the simpler your solutions get. In that sense, simplicity is not the opposite of complexity from a technical point of view, but from an implementation point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Principles of writing&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing articles and code samples since February 2006 and my top priority is to write original material every time and not just link to or reference some other articles that I find interesting. Secondly, the code samples must always adhere to my coding principles, which also make them easier to understand and implement.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Whenever I write articles about abstract development subjects without code samples, they have to carry a punch of personal opinion and never be negative by nature. I don’t like reading negative articles so that’s why I don’t write them my self.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  <keywords>mads, developer, coding</keywords>
  <datecreated>2007-03-29 22:33:42</datecreated>
  <datemodified>0001-01-01 00:00:00</datemodified>
</page>